<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ayden Cole</title>
        <description>Bracia is a simple personal blog theme for Jekyll.</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 19:49:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 19:49:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hello World!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Ayden, and I am a 25 year old Pacific NorthWest native. I love to run and hike the local trails like Timberline Trail which loops all the way around Mt. Hood. I also enjoy scifi shows and I’ve recently been getting into cooking. My professional background is in healthcare and mental health. I majored with a Bachelors of Science in Psychology at Oklahoma Christian University, and I’ve worked at places like Cascadia Behavioral Healthcare, Amen Clinic, and Compass Oncology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently started a career switch from healthcare to cybersecurity. I felt like I had plateaued and work wasn’t making me grow. I remembered back in high school when I took a free online course called “Learn Python the Hard Way” by Zed Shaw. The constant challenges and new lessons kept me captivated for months. So I figured I would revisit the world of the internet of things, and take a free course from Cisco called “Introduction to Cybersecurity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/07-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;California&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/ourQHRTE2IM&quot;&gt;Alex Kotliarskyi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a concussion on one of my adventures on Mt. Hood and the doctor said to take a week off work. During that time, I found that even though I could barely focus for a few minutes at a time and I wasn’t really supposed to look at screens, I kept returning to the “Introduction to Cybersecurity” course, and I quickly finished it. It opened up a new, scifi-esque world of threats, risks, and vulnerabilities in a swiftly evolving cyber landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity was a way to engage with the world in a new and exciting way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired, I went on Coursera and signed up for the Google Cybersecurity Certificate. In less than a month, I had earned my certificate and significantly increased my knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/07-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rest&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@rpnickson&quot;&gt;Roberto Nickson&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another trip back from Cloud Cap on Mt. Hood, I was listening to Episode 22 of “The I.T. Career Podcast” with Christophe Limpalair, and he recommended making a blog to document what you’re learning. Limpalair listed two benefits of starting a blog. One is that by teaching others, you actually learn better yourself. Second is that you can preserve a record of your expanding knowledge base for future employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I asked an AI assistant, Grok, what the most secure way to build a website was and how to turn it into a learning lab. I will get more into the recipe Grok provided and my own modifications in a future blog post. It was quite a steep learning curve, but here we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to the future, I have just bought vouchers for the CompTIA Security+ and CompTIA Network+ and I am stoked prepare for those. I will be documenting my progress here, as well as any other interesting cybersecurity lessons I learn along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for joining me on this journey!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:31:05 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/first-post-ever</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/first-post-ever</guid>
                
                <category>study</category>
                
                <category>personal</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>